#### Contact

Hyderabad 9396776677 (Mobile) ndrao2001@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/raonippuleti-61706318 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Supply Chain Management Process Manufacturing ERP

## Languages

English (Professional Working)
Telugu (Native or Bilingual)
Tamil (Professional Working)
kannada (Limited Working)
Hindi (Limited Working)

## Certifications

JDE Multiple Modules-Ware House,GA,FA etc JDE Demand Scheduling MFG Accounting

1. JDE General Accounting Rel 8.11 Ed 1 PRV

JDE Inventory

# Rao Nippuleti

Supply Chain Professional with Oracle JDE ERP @ Across USA / Africa/India Locations in the areas of Chemicals APIs,Flavours/ Organic,Pharma,Oil &Gas, Agro Produce,FMCG,Exports&Imports. Hyderabad

## Summary

Over 30 years of Experience with proven background in Chemicals-APIs(Bulk), Flavours/Organic, Specialty oils and Consumer Package Goods industry. Agriculture Produce & Demonstrated wide range of experience in end to end Supply chain integrated solutions. New Product Development, Sourcing, Manufacturing & Kaizen Concepts/ TQM and logistics Management coupled with JDEdwards ERP integration in all supply modules across different projects in North America, Africa, Middle East, India.

# Experience

GREEN ASIA IMPEX PRIVATE LIMITED Director Of Operations October 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 4 months) India

Led Operations and Planning includes Exports & Imports, Procurement from Farmers and Markets, Customer base enhancement, Monitored shipments, liners and required documentations. Maintained Large Ware Houses-Cold &Dry.

Monitored quality parameters of the products. Responsible for P&L, Manpower Planning. Handling contract Processors of peppers. Attended International food Exhibition at "GERMANY" and One to One meeting with Customers at "CHINA".

#### SYSTIME >KPIT >Birlasoft

Senior Functional Manager-ERP -Oracle JD Edwards February 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 7 months)

Houston, Texas Area

>Handled Multiple clients over 12 locations at site in USA.

Responsible for Supply Chain ERP systems Roll outs in USA and Canadian location-JD Edwards v9.0

Onsite-Offshore Coordination. Location: Buffalo / Niagara.

- PRAXAIR @ Buffalo: Responsible for Supply Chain ERP systems Implementation and post implementation support including Onsite Coordination.
- Thermofisher @ Sandiego
- a) Configuration of EDI interfaces for PO Acknowledgement, ASN and Invoicing
- b) Confidential Project, Co-ordination with Comergent E Commerce, Ariba, Liasion and Oracle Fusion Middleware Teams to track order processing on B2B model. Configurator .
- c) Led Configuration of EDI, Scheduling jobs and Co-ordinated with European, Singapore Order processing teams.
- Weatherford @ Houston
- a) Consolidation of shipments from various sourcing points to Destination point in Other countries.
- b) Worked with 3rd Party Logistic providers(DB Schenker), SOA integration teams and Client Functional BA's to have data sync between Weatherford and 3rd party systems on Shipment receipts, acceptance and consolidation.
- Hill-Rom –Indiana, USA- Medical devices /Hospital Beds Manufacturing company

**Project Details** 

Duration: Mar – April 2018

Project: Knowledge Transition

Role: Transition Functional Manager

Environment: Platform: JD Edwards Enterprise One v9.0

Project Scope & Responsibilities

- a) Worked with Onsite Client BA's from Functional perspective of Sales and Distribution, Configurator, Advance Pricing. Procurement and Inventory areas.
- b) Transitioned the mentioned functional areas to offshore folks on time.

CARDINAL HEALTH PHARMACEUTICAL LLC-contract TCS USA

Functional Consultant- JDEdwards

September 2016 - January 2017 (5 months)

Columbus, Ohio Area & Miami ,Florida

•FDA controlled environment, Document validation and control is more thrust and rigorously watched area.

- •Supporting Customized JDE applications with Interfaces of Manugistics for planning, DSI-Tran collector for Inventory. Standard process of Purchase, AR / AP and GL.
- •24-\*7 support environment, Monitored tickets through Service now and acted as per priorities.

DELOITTE & TOUCHE USA, LLP-contract Consultant- Oracle ERP JD Edwards April 2013 - March 2016 (3 years) Indianapolis, Indiana Area& Manhattan

Project: Calumet Specialty (Indiana)& Briefly at Birch box-Manhattan(NYC) Environment: Oracle JDE Enterprise 9.0 /9.1

## Roles and Responsibilities: As Consultant

- Conduct Business process analysis workshops, requirements determination, mapping, GAP analysis, configuration, work around, testing, user training, documentation, go-live, post production support and enhancements in the areas of Order to Cash- Configured various type of Ordering Process-Regular / Inter branch / Inter Company / RMA / Credit / Sample Orders, EDI. Inventory- Defined commitment process, Cycle counts and time to time solving Integration related, Transportation, Advance pricing- defining complex groups, Schedules, Adjustment Names, Free goods, Rebates, Discounts etc , Work Order Processing, Order to Cash integration with Finance- AR AP GL ,Procure to Pay-Configuring Approval process, Receipt routing and Project based Purchasing .RSS. Exposure to Manufacturing\_ Product Data Management, MRP, Discreet and Process Manufacturing.
- Prepared Testing plan, scripts and schedules for UAT and Integration testing
- Provided Post Production support, Re engineering and enhancements which including writing Functional specifications, technical specifications, configuration changes, testing and system documentation
- Assisted Technical consultants in understanding project requirements and assisted them in defining new functionality and Business Function changes.
- Inventory Stabilization, Work order process design and SOW preparation for further implementation design.

IBM Global Business Process Services Project Lead March 2009 - April 2013 (4 years 2 months)

Implementation and Supporting JDE ERP systems (Enterprise one and worldsoft) in Distribution area of SARALEE- Coffee & Tea- North America.

Roles and Responsibilities: Created functional specification documents in consultation with business towards data pushing from JDE Via web methods to Siperion systems. Understanding other interfaces requirements, creating test scripts, testing etc.,

Project 2: Mar 09 to May 12 Client: Saralee (North America) Project lead Environment: Oracle JD Edwards A.7.3. (Enterprise Resource Planning), AS/400, Enterprise 9.0.

Team Size: 11

Roles and Responsibilities: Client is a Giant Food Manufacturer world wide, Project Lead for an onsite – Offshore model of AMS. Coordinated with transition team, which involved the following primary responsibilities: requirements gathering, aid with docs preparation, organizing KT and reverse KT SAS70 Audit preparation, support and maintenance of JDE Distribution (Sales, Inventory, Procurement, Advance Pricing, Warehousing) Finance, and Manufacturing modules, critical incident management, testing of IT controls with business processes, PO and SO operations mapped to EDI interfaces, World Writer, and Dream Writer configurations. Also SOX compliance monitoring

Mahindra Satyam, Align tefchnology (Mfrs of Dental Invagilins @ USA, West Africa Cements @Africa
JDE ERP systems in Distribution
2006 - 2009 (3 years)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India, Santaclara, USA

Led a team of software professionals ,Involved in Implementation,rollouts and support projects for JDE -ERP systems of Supply chain for US/Africa/Dubai clients on Onsite -Offshore model.

## Gulf Oil

Logistics Manager- Planning & Inventory Control 2006 - 2006 (less than a year)

Headed planning department of Pharmaceutial division

**HPCL** 

ERP Consultant

2005 - 2006 (1 year)

HPCL (fortune 500) Asia's largest JDE Implementation, India

Environment: Oracle JD Edwards XE,B7333.

Team Size: 40

Roles and Responsibilities: Modules covered-Full suite in JDE. It was a complete rollout and onsite support. As a project team member, was responsible for Transportation Module configuration in terms of vehicle, carrier, route and rate setups. Also responsible for functional specs for reports, supervision of end-user training in Sales, Distribution, Advance Pricing and Transportation modules. Prepared user training documentation.

Reckitt Benckiser Supply Chain Professional 1990 - 2004 (14 years)

.

Roles and Responsibilities: Project core member for Manufacturing, Distribution, Finance modules.

Business analysis and gap identification conducted, configuration setups, development of functional specs for reports, like Purchase Order, and Invoice, acknowledgement note. Also responsible for testing and deployment of reports, user manual preparation, Sales, Inventory, Purchase modules and

end user training and documentation.

Reckitt Benckiser India Ltd -14 ½ YEARS (Domain & ERP Functional Exp) 1990 to 04

An European Fortune 500 into FMCG / pharma existing in 180 countries, Mfrs of Dettol, Disprin, Mortein, Cherry blossom etc.,

At Hosur (TN)-1990 to 1998

Led and monitored Logistics, Inventory and Manufacturing operations of Basic Drugs-Triclosan, Sucralfate, PCMX (which is main PFI in Detttol), Aroma Chemicals, Food Chemicals and it's yields, quality systems, safety.

Involved in Sales and Operational Planning

Inventory Management, Unit Operations.

PCMX yield improved, awarded GOLD MEDAL as Kaizen.

Ensured and supported real time updating of ERP entries of Logistics.

Instrumental in Vendor Development towards sourcing of Raw & packaging Material

Education

Vinayaka Mission's Research Foundation - University MBA, General Management · (2005 - 2005)

An Organisation of Ministry of MSME, Govt of India

Post Diploma, Logistics and Supply Chain Management · (July 2004 - 2005)

PSG Tech - Entrepreneurs Club Diploma, Enterprise Management · (1997 - 1998)

Andhra University
B.SC, Chemistry · (1983 - 1986)